rentfaster.ca 2019-11-07

# RentFaster.ca - Privacy Policy - RentFaster.ca

### RENTFASTER.CA INC. WEBSITE PRIVACY POLICY

At RentFaster.ca Inc. ("RentFaster"), we are committed to maintaining the accuracy, confidentiality and security of your personal information. We have developed this website privacy policy to describe our privacy practices and how we collect, use and disclose the personal information of those individuals who visit www.rentfaster.ca (the "Site") or use the information or services that we offer through the Site (the "Services").

Please take a minute to read this policy so that you understand how we treat your personal information. If you are unsure if or how this privacy policy applies to you, please contact our Privacy Officer, whose contact information is listed below, for more information. 

### What is Personal Information?

For the purposes of this privacy policy, personal information is any information about an identifiable individual, other than the person's business title or business contact information when used or disclosed for the purpose of business communications.

### What Personal Information Do We Collect?

You may visit the Site and access certain Services without telling us who you are or revealing any information about yourself, including your e-mail address. Our web server, however, may collect information related to your visit to the Site or the Services, including the IP address and domain used to access the Site or the Services, the type and version of your browser, the website you came from to access the Site or the Services, the page you entered and exited at, any pages that are viewed by that IP address and what country you are from. We use this information to monitor the Site's and Services' performance (such as number of visits, average time spent per page, number of page views) and for our business purposes such as working to continually upgrade the Site and Services.

We may collect personal information from you, such as your name, e-mail address, postal address, phone number, and credit card number, when you access some Services, including creating a user account, listing a property online, saving your preferences online, signing up for e-mail alerts, or contacting us with a question or concern. We maintain a record of your preferences and the Services you use and may combine this information with information about you that we acquire from our marketing partners, from unrelated third parties, and possibly from our other brands.

### Why Do We Collect, Use, and Disclose Personal Information? 

In addition to the specific purposes that we may advise you of at or before the time that we collect your personal information, we may also collect personal information from you so that we may: 

  * enable you to access or otherwise use the Services; 
  * learn more about your preferences; 
  * establish, maintain, enhance, and manage your experience; 
  * analyze trends and statistics; 
  * review and improve the Services that we provide to you; 
  * communicate with you and send you information by e-mail, postal mail, telephone, text message, or other means about our Services, unless you have directed us not to contact you with promotional communications; 
  * address problems with and improve our site design, and Services; 
  * protect against error, fraud, theft and damage to our goods and property; and 
  * comply with applicable law or regulatory requirements. 

We may also use your contact information to provide you with notifications regarding the Site or Services, such as any future amendments to this policy, and may disclose such information in response to a law enforcement agency or other public agency's lawful request or if we feel that such disclosure may prevent the instigation of a crime, facilitate an investigation related to public safety or protect the safety of a user using the Site or Services, protect the security or integrity of the Site and Services, or enable us to take precautions against liability.

Your personal information may be shared with our employees, contractors, consultants, affiliates and other parties who require such information to assist us with establishing, maintaining and managing our relationship with you or developing, operating and maintaining the Site and Services. Examples of third parties with whom we may share your personal information include our service providers who manage our customer information and perform services on our behalf, and other companies that we may collaborate with to offer or provide products, services, or promotions to our customers. In addition, your personal information may be disclosed or transferred to another party in the event of a change in ownership of, or a grant of a security interest in, all or a part of RentFaster. 

Further, your personal information may be disclosed: 

  * as permitted or required by applicable law or regulatory requirements (for example, in response to a court order or a subpoena); 
  * to protect the rights and property of RentFaster; 
  * during emergency situations or where necessary to protect the safety of a person or group of persons; 
  * where the personal information is publicly available; or 
  * with your consent. 

You acknowledge and agree that access to and use of this Site and the Services is provided via the Internet and that your information, including personal information, may be transferred across national borders and stored or processed in any country in the world. We may collect, use or disclose your personal information without your knowledge or consent where we are permitted or required by applicable law or regulatory requirements to do so.

In addition, our third party service providers may provide certain information technology and data processing services to us from time to time so that we may operate our business, and as result, your personal information may be collected, used, processed, stored or disclosed in the United States of America.

### We may send you E-mail.

From time to time we may e-mail important information to you regarding the Site or the Services, including for example, changes to our service offerings, e-mails advising you that your listing may be expiring shortly, and e-mails containing your forgotten password.

In addition, where you request information from us, we may use the e-mail address that you provide to send you information about offers on products and services that we believe may be of interest to you. If you do not wish to receive such e-mails, you may opt out of receiving same by simply telling us when you give us your personal information or register with us. If you later change your mind, you may advise us at any time to indicate that you now wish to, or no longer wish to, receive these messages.

If you have asked us to put you on an e-mail mailing list to provide you with certain information on a regular basis, you may ask us to remove you from the list at any time (using the unsubscribe instructions provided with each e-mail and on the Site or Service where you signed up).

### E-mail surveillance and retention

You may e-mail other users directly through the e-mail service available on the Site. For the purpose of protecting our users from spam and offensive e-mails, our e-mail delivery system may automatically alert us to any instance in which a user sends: (i) what we deem to be an unwarranted or otherwise inordinate amounts of e-mails; and (ii) an e-mail containing profanity. You hereby consent that our e-mail delivery system may monitor all e-mails exchanged between users on the Site for the foregoing purpose. You acknowledge and agree that we have the right, but not the obligation, to review all such e-mails, and to decide whether to block their delivery to their intended recipient.

We may keep all copies of any e-mails sent through the Site in accordance with our record retention policy, but in any event, no longer as is reasonably required for us to comply with all applicable laws.

### How Do We Use Cookies?

When you visit the Site or Services, we may place a "cookie" on the hard drive of your computer to track your visit. A cookie is a small data file that is transferred to your hard drive through your web browser that can only be read by the website that placed the cookie on your hard drive. The cookie acts as an identification card and allows the Site to identify you and to record your passwords and preferences. The cookie allows us to track your visit to the Site or Services so that we can better understand your use of the Site and Services so that we can customize and tailor it to better meet your needs. For example, our cookies help us to learn about the usage of the Site and Services by helping us to track how many visitors we have, how often they visit various sections of the Site and Services, and their geographic location.

**Please note:** Cookies cannot harm your computer and do not contain any personal or private information.

Most web browsers are set to accept cookies. However, on most web browsers you may change this setting to have your web browser either: (1) notify you prior to a website placing a cookie on your hard drive so that you can decide whether or not to accept the cookie; or (2) automatically prevent the placing of a cookie on your hard drive. It should be noted that if cookies are not accepted, you will not be able to access a number of web pages found on the Site. 

### How Do We Use Pixel Tags?

"Pixel tags" are tiny graphic images placed on certain pages of our Site but not on your computer. When you access these pages, pixel tags generate a generic notice of that visit.

We may use pixel tags help us measure the effectiveness of the Site and our advertising and assess our customers' online choices. We typically work with third-party service providers that help us track, collect, analyze and otherwise use this information.

There may be times when we may combine the information we collect through pixel tags with cookies and other information we have collected from you. This information may be used to improve the Site, to personalize your online experience, to tailor our communications with you, to determine the effectiveness of our advertising, and for other internal business purposes.

### Your Consent is Important to Us

By using the Site or Services, you are consenting to the collection, use and disclosure of your personal information as explained in this privacy policy.

If you later change your mind, you may advise us at any time to indicate your privacy preferences and to specify how we may collect, use or disclose your personal information.

In addition, you may change or withdraw your consent at any time, subject to legal or contractual restrictions and reasonable notice, by contacting our Privacy Officer using the contact information set out below. In some circumstances, a change in or withdrawal of consent may severely limit our ability to provide products or services to you. All communications with respect to such withdrawal or variation of consent should be in writing and addressed to our Privacy Officer.

### How is Your Personal Information Protected?

When you enter your personal information on the Site when making an applicable payment to us, we use Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) technology to protect your information as it is transmitted to us. While we have in place this, along with other physical, contractual, electronic and managerial safeguards to seek to protect the security and privacy of your personal information that are appropriate to the sensitivity of the personal information in question, please be aware that: (i) no security measures are perfect or impenetrable; and (ii) no data transmission over the Internet can be guaranteed to be 100% secure. As a result, while this Site and the Services strive to protect your personal information, we cannot warrant the confidentiality or security of any information you transmit to us, and you do so at your own risk.

The security of your personal information is important to us, please advise our Privacy Officer immediately of any incident involving the loss of or unauthorized access to or disclosure of personal information that is in our custody or control.

### Phishing

Phishing is the practice of tricking someone into giving confidential information. Examples include falsely claiming to be a legitimate company when sending an e-mail to a user, in an attempt to get the user to send private information that will be used for identity theft and fraud.

We will never ask you to send any personal details via e-mail. If we require such details, for security reasons we will ask you to contact us by phone. Should you receive an e-mail claiming to be from RentFaster.ca requesting this kind of information, please do not respond but let us know.

Always be cautious about the information you provide or store online.

### Special Notes about Children

Consistent with our obligations under various child privacy protection laws, we do not knowingly collect, use, disclose or store personal information of children under eighteen (18) years of age. Our Site is intended for a general audience and is not targeted to or intended for use by children.

If we receive actual knowledge that a person is under the age of eighteen (18) and has registered without the permission of his or her parent or guardian to use the Site, we will remove from our files all personally identifiable registration information about that individual. 

### What about Third Party Advertisements or Links to other Websites?

You should also be aware that companies that link to our Site or may be found from links from our Site may use their own cookies. This Policy does not cover how these companies use their cookies.

Our Site and Services may contain links to other websites that may be subject to less stringent privacy standards. We cannot assume any responsibility for the privacy practices, policies or actions of the third parties that operate these websites. RentFaster is not responsible for how such third parties collect, use or disclose your personal information. You should review the privacy policies of these websites before providing them with personal information.

### Updating Your Personal Information

It is important that the information contained in our records is both accurate and current. If your personal information happens to change during the course of our relationship, please keep us informed of such changes. 

In some circumstances we may not agree with your request to change your personal information and will instead append an alternative text to the record in question.

### Access to Your Personal Information

You can ask to see the personal information that we hold about you. If you want to review, verify or correct your personal information, please contact our Privacy Officer using the contact information set out below. Please note that any such communication must be in writing.

When requesting access to your personal information, please note that we may request specific information from you to enable us to confirm your identity and right to access, as well as to search for and provide you with the personal information that we hold about you. We may charge you a fee to access your personal information; however, we will advise you of any fee in advance.

Your right to access the personal information that we hold about you is not absolute. There are instances where applicable law or regulatory requirements allow or require us to refuse to provide some or all of the personal information that we hold about you. In addition, the personal information may have been destroyed, erased or made anonymous in accordance with our record retention obligations and practices.

### Inquiries or Concerns? 

For questions about our privacy policy, to make choices about receiving promotional communications, or to update your personal information, you can contact us by e-mail, telephone, fax or postal mail at:

Privacy Officer  
RentFaster.ca Inc.  
909 17th Avenue SW  
Calgary AB, T2T 0A4  
E-mail: info@rentfaster.ca  
Phone: 1-587-318-2876  
Fax: 587-318-2876

### Application and Interpretation of this Privacy Policy

It is our policy to comply with the privacy legislation within each jurisdiction in which we operate. Sometimes the privacy legislation and/or an individual's right to privacy are different from one jurisdiction to another. This privacy policy has a limited scope and application. Consequently, the rights and obligations contained in this privacy policy may not be available to all individuals or in all jurisdictions. 

Any interpretation associated with this privacy policy will be made by our Privacy Officer. This privacy policy includes examples but is not intended to be restricted in its application to such examples, therefore where the word 'including' is used, it shall mean 'including without limitation'.

This privacy policy does not create or confer upon any individual any rights, or impose upon RentFaster any rights or obligations outside of, or in addition to, any rights or obligations imposed by applicable laws. Should there be, in a specific case, any inconsistency between this privacy policy and such laws, this privacy policy shall be interpreted, in respect of that case, to give effect to, and comply with, such laws.

### Modifications to this Privacy Policy

From time to time, we may make changes to this privacy policy to reflect changes in our legal or regulatory obligations or in the manner in which we deal with your personal information. We will post any revised version of this privacy policy on the Site and encourage you to refer back to it on a regular basis. This privacy policy was last updated August 1, 2011.

### Interpretation of this Privacy Policy

Any interpretation associated with this privacy policy will be made by our Privacy Officer. This privacy policy includes examples but is not intended to be restricted in its application to such examples; therefore, where the word "including" is used, it shall mean "including without limitation".
